Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 27.
We are going to explain the functionality of the following function.
It is written in C so function f one function, one take into parameter and n and do the following stuff.
It starts with equal to zero, which initializing equal to zero.
Check if n greater than one.
It will call again the function one and pass and minus one.
So this is a recursion occurs here.
OK.
Otherwise it will go and continue for a loop and the print and print the star, according to Idlis and
starting from I equate to zero and following all and passing all the elements from zero to an Eilat's,
then OK, post the video and think about it, what is the result and how the functionality of this function
works as the previous use?
We have explained.
OK, please come into your solution and the comments below.
Let's start.
We have I will tell you, I told you to take always an example.
So I will take an equal to five.
OK.
So at the first iteration.
I.
Is equal to zero.
Or at the first execution, if any, greater than one.
Yes, and equal to five call function and minus one.
So this will lead to function.
Of fought.
So this is half of life.
OK, let me explain it better.
I remove this.
And F of five calls, F of four again, f of four.
You see guys that here at the stop.
It does not execute that loop because as I told you, the algorithm and the pattern that recursion,
execute and follows is executing and calling the methods until it get back.
That results and then it go to the next lines and execute the following codes.
So for stops here at sort of four five stops here as four four, it goes up and equal to zero and greater
than one.
Yes, and equal to four.
So it will execute f of three and call F of three without continuing to do.
Go through this.
OK.
This is the trick behind recursion.
OK, now three, again, it will call F2 and f of two, it will call F of what F1 here are equal to
zero.
Yes, and greater than one.
No one is not the greater than one.
So this will be skipped and it will go and execute this for loop.
OK.
This for a loop.
It will start from printing from equal to zero.
And still, I less than and which is one.
Which is one.
And plus plus, okay, it will print off.
From zero.
It will print only one star.
OK.
Now we have finished off of one.
Okay.
This is the iteration of of one.
But F of two and three and four and five, they are opened and they need to continue their execution
and execute this for a loop.
So this is due to f of one.
OK, f off one f of one calls again f of two and tell it to continue its loop.
So four zero two two.
So f of two equal.
It will go through.
And sprint from zero, it said, Lou, are equal to zero and less then and and and is equal to two.
So from zero to two, there is two zero and one because I less than and not equal.
OK.
Two.
So it will print two stars.
Okay, this is f of an f and calls again f of three and tell it to continue its slope.
So f of three.
Will continue, and it will print from zero to three three is not included, so it will print one two
zero one two stars.
OK, f of three calls back A for four and it will print four stars OK, from zero two four four four.
It calls F of five to continue its loop because it stopped here and it will print this.
From zero to five.
OK.
Five is not included, zero is inaccurate.
You see, guys, how many stars have been printing?
This is.
This is how this function works, so if we print that, if we see the variables.
The stars.
This is the pattern.
OK.
Of an equal to five.
OK and equal to five.
So how to find the pattern, we need to know how this algorithm.
And based on so it it is based on, we start with an.
Times how many times and minus one, five times for over two.
So five times four is twenty over two.
We have.
It's not here, it's plus and into any plus one over two, because one two three plus three is six plus
four, then plus five is equal to 20.
So.
Five times six is equal to 30.
And we have 15 stars, so sorry, it is not 20.
It is 15 stars, so five, according to this equation, five times six of us, two is equal to 15.
This is the number of stars that we have in this.
So the following functions.
The following function is based on this formula and into any +1 over to always when you see this increasing
order according to their line use and end to end +1 over two.
This is the trick of this question.